（ナルト）ヘッヘヘ。　あんな積み木遊び→
Playing with those building blocks,
今の俺様に　かかれば
わけないぜ。
it's a given I was able to complete it,
at my level now.
（キラービー）フン…
あんなもん　できて当然！
You're expected to do
something like that.
次は　簡単には通せん。
The next one won't be easy,
that's a fact.
へぇ～　九尾とチャクラを取り合った
あの部屋に　つながってたんだ。
Oh... So this is connected to that room
where I scrambled with Nine Tails.
よく　見ろ。
Take a good look.
今度は　八尾の石像…。
This time,
it's a statue of the Eight Tails.
いちいち　めんどくせえ。
This is a drag every time!
ここは　また　別の部屋の入り口！
Here's the entrance to another room.
尾獣の修業の　最終段階。
黙れ　愚痴！
For the final Tailed Beast training!
Now stop complaining!
これから　人柱力が使う
最強の術を教える。　オーライ？
I'm gonna teach you
the most powerful jutsu for a Jinchuriki.
準備は　オーケー？
What do you say?
Preparations okay?
うん！　ちゃんと　モノにして
コントロールしきっとかねえとな。
Right! I have to know how
to control stuff.
で　まず　なにすんの？
So? What do I do first?
尾獣モードで　尾獣化しろ。
Transform into a Tailed Beast
in Tailed Beast mode!
ここが　オー　一番！
This is number one.
Now it's your turn!
次は　お前の番！　オー　急ぎ～！
Hurry and get it done.
危なくねえかな？
Isn't that dangerous?
尾獣化するのは
ちょっと怖えんだけど…。
Transforming into a Tailed Beast
is sorta scary.
今の　お前なら大丈夫だ。
バカ野郎。　この野郎。
You can do it now, fool, ya fool.
純粋な尾獣のチャクラだけ
取り出した。
'Cuz you can draw out
pure Tailed Beast chakra.
暴走はない。　トンチキ野郎！
It's not gonna run wild, ya fool!
じゃあ…。
Well then...
うぅ～っ！
更に　尾獣まで　イメージ！　クソ野郎！
Visualize your Tailed Beast, ya fool!
うぉ～っ！！
コンコン…。
きっつ…。
駄目か…　残念。
Can't, huh? Too bad.
九尾と　本当に　仲よく
なったわけじゃ　ないからな。
Well, it's not like you're pals
with the Nine Tails...
尾獣化は　惨敗。
Anyway, Tailed Beast Transformation
is a dismal failure.
（八尾）じゃあ
どうやって教えんだ？　尾獣球。
So how are you going to teach him
the Tailed Beast Bomb?
ありゃ　人柱力でも→
That's the first trick
a Jinchuriki can use
尾獣化して
初めて使える技だぜ　ビー。
after going into Tailed Beast State, Bee.
はぁ～　疲れたってばよ～。
Man, I'm dead tired.
結構　九尾チャクラ使ったのに
無理なのかよ…。
So I used the Nine-Tails' chakra
all for nothing?
それに　この尾獣モードのリスクも→
By the way... shouldn't you tell him that
this Tailed Beast mode is risky?
教えといたほうが
いいんじゃねえか？
ビー　お前とナルトじゃ
根本的に　リスクが違うぞ。
Bee, the risk for you and Naruto
is fundamentally different.
つうか　俺が説明する。　表に出せ。
Look, I'll explain. Let me out.
そのへん　ゴチャゴチャ　バトンタッチ！
俺は　タジタジ。
I hand over the baton
for the mumble jumble
Saves me from the verbal fumble...
おい　ナルト　俺は　八尾だ。
ビーじゃねえ。
Hey! Naruto!
I'm the Eight Tails, not Bee.
これから　言うことを　よ～く聞け。
Now listen carefully
to what I tell you!
ん～　なんか　ややこしいな～。
Man, this is so complicated.
まぁ　変なダジャレが　ない分
聞きやすいか。
But you don't talk in rhymes,
so it's easier to understand.
まずは　尾獣チャクラモードに
なったときの　リスクだ。
First, I'll go over the risk when you switch
to Tailed Beast chakra mode.
リスク…　リスク　あんの！？　このモード！
Risk?
There's a risk to this mode?!
おおありだ！　大事なことだから
黙って聞くんだぞ。
Big time!
It's very important,
so be quiet and listen.
お…　おっす！
Y-Yeah...
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
I was asleep all this time, I kept quiet all this time
zutto nemutteta zutto damatteta
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I can see something far away
tooku ni nanika ga mieru
something more important now than studying
benkyou yori mo ima taisetsu na mono
hey, it's calling us, hey, let's go
ooi yonde iru ooi itte mi yo
I think we can find it
mitsukarisou nanda
it's infinite, it's infinite, it's infinite, rock assault
eien desu eien desu eien desu totsugeki rock
see, you can overtake the future
mirai wa hora oinuite
this ship can really fly through the sky
hontou wa sora toberu fune
Secrets of the Reanimation Jutsu
尾獣チャクラモードに　なったときのリスク…
それはだ。
The risk when you switch to
Tailed Beast chakra mode...
うん！
That's...!
基本　尾獣チャクラモードを使ってる間→
Yes?
"NARUTO
NINE-TAILS' CHAKRA
OWN CHAKRA"
Basically, when you're in
Tailed Beast chakra mode,
お前自身の　ナルトチャクラが
九尾に取られている。
your own personal Naruto chakra is
being taken by the Nine Tails!
ナルトチャクラを　いったん棚上げして→
Because you momentarily
shelve your own chakra
九尾チャクラを　使うからな。
うん…。
in order to use the Nine Tails' chakra.
もちろん　ナルトチャクラを取られ続け
ゼロに　なれば→
"OWN CHAKRA"
So of course, if your own chakra
is emptied out completely...
ちゃんと　あの世行きだ。
"ZERO"
you're a goner.
えぇ～っ！？
Huh?! But how come
Mr Eight Tails is okay?!
じゃあ　なんで　タコのおっさんは
大丈夫なんだってばよ？
お前は　九尾チャクラを取っただけで→
Even if you take over
the Nine Tails' chakra,
本当の意味で　九尾を
手なずけてるわけじゃねえ。
you haven't really tamed him.
俺とビーも　昔は　そうだった。
Bee and I were like that in the past.
チャクラを　取り合ってたもんだ。
We competed for each other's chakra.
それと　尾獣チャクラモードで
影分身は　使わないほうがいい。
Oh and, you shouldn't
use Shadow Clones
when you're in
Tailed Beast chakra mode.
ナルトチャクラが　分身した人数分
取られていく。
Shadow Clones made from
your own chakra will be taken.
一気に　なくなって　死ぬぞ。
They'll be gone in an instant,
and you'll die.
ふ～ん　ヘヘッ。
でも　俺のチャクラってば
漏れ出してた九尾チャクラを→
But my chakra takes the Nine Tails' chakra
that's been leaking
カンゲンしてるとかなんとかで…
まぁ　いっぱいあるから。
and reconstitutes it or whatever...
so I have lots.
アホ！　九尾の力を　ナメんなよ！
Fool! Don't underestimate
the Nine Tails!
お前のチャクラ　ガンガン　取ってくぞ！
He'll wipe out your chakra!
取られたナルトチャクラを回復するには→
Restoring your stolen
chakra takes time!
それなりの時間がかかる！
注意しろ。
調子こいて
戦闘中　九尾チャクラばっか使うと→
So be careful!
If you get carried away and
use only the Nine Tails' chakra in battle,
いつの間にか　死ぬからな。
なっ…！
you'll end up dead.
本来は　己と尾獣とで→
W-Wha...?
By rights, you and the Tailed Beast should
negotiate how you both use chakra.
チャクラのやりとりを
交渉して決めるもんだ。
九尾は　そんなことをする
タイプじゃないがな。
But Nine Tails isn't the type to do that.
それと　九尾から→
綱引きで取った九尾チャクラも
限りがある。
Also, there's a limit to the chakra
you managed to tug out of the Nine Tails.
リスクでけえ…。
So much risk...
それなのに人柱力の
最高の術もできねえのか…。
And yet, I can't use
a Jinchuriki's ultimate jutsu?
まあよ…　尾獣玉はあきらめろ…。
Well, forget about
Tailed Beast Bomb.
お前の必殺技を
更に鍛えたほうが　まだマシだ。
You should just concentrate on
polishing up your special moves.
尾獣玉？　それって　どんな術だ？
Tailed Beast Bomb?
What kind of jutsu is that?
な～に　簡単だ。
Oh, it's simple.
己のチャクラを形態変化させて→
You take your chakra and
change its form...
口に溜めて圧縮…
んで　それを放つだけ。
gather it up and compress it...
Then just spew it out.
《あれか…》
Like that time...
ちょうど　ゲロを吐く感覚に似てる。
It's almost like vomiting.
なら　このモードのままやってみる！
I wanna try it in this mode!
うっ…！
《この感じか！？》
Like this?!
ウエ～…。
尾獣化してないと無理だ。
It's impossible without
Tailed Beast Transformation.
とりあえず　説明はした…。
Anyway, I've explained it all to you.
もう　ビーに変わる。
I'm gonna switch with Bee.
しかたねえ…　断念だ。
Oh well, too bad.
It can't be helped.
お前の必殺技を　尾獣チャクラモードで→
You just have to do your special move
in Tailed Beast chakra mode, is all...
やってみるくらいしかねえな…
丹念に。
螺旋丸は
影分身しねえとできねえから→
Rasengan requires Shadow Clone Jutsu,
so it's not suited to this mode.
このモードは向いてねえよ。
チャクラの放出係と
回転　圧縮して留める→
Chakra release and rotation...
形態変化の係の
２人分の手が必要で…。
plus change in chakra form
and compression...
That's a two-person move.
尾獣チャクラ
お前の手足と同じ感覚。
Tailed Beast chakra...
Your own hands and feet,
that's the sensation.
本物の手足と錯覚。
And the real ones, are just an illusion.
なるほど…。
I see...
こんな感じかな。
なかなか　上出来！
Maybe like this?
Not bad at all.
とりあえず
あの必殺技をやってみろ。
Try that special move of yours.
That move you already have.
まずは　出来合い。
よ～し！
螺旋丸！
All right!
Rasengan!
あれ！？
これは…！
Huh?!
回転　圧縮して留める
形態変化の…。
This is...!
Change in chakra form with
rotation and compression...
うわっ！
《その術！
尾獣玉と　そっくりだぞ。
That jutsu!
It's exactly like the Tailed Beast Bomb,
fool, ya fool!
バカ野郎　この野郎》
おい　ナルト…。
Hey! Naruto!
その術　誰に教わった？
このトンチキ野郎！
Who taught you that jutsu,
ya dimwit?!
え？　あぁ…　エロ仙人が…。
Huh?! Well, it was Pervy Sage...
あぁ…　自来也先生から教わった。
I mean, Jiraiya Sensei.
でも　術を作ったのは
四代目火影だけどもさ！
But the Fourth Hokage invented it.
《四代目火影…　なんて偶然だ。
Fourth Hokage...?
What a coincidence.
Or maybe fate?
運命か…　驚異！》
螺旋丸！　これは尾獣玉と
そっくりのやり方…　共通！
Truly not a shame!
Rasengan!
The method is exactly the same
as Tailed Beast Bomb.
尾獣の　この技を参考に
考案された術！
It's exactly the same!
Created with
the Tailed Beast Bomb in mind!
それが　螺旋丸だったんだ！
That's the Rasengan!
まるで　お前に尾獣玉を
託すためかのごとく…　強運！
It's like he entrusted you with
the Tailed Beast Bomb.
You couldn't have been luckier.
尾獣化してやると簡単だが→
It's easy when you're in
Tailed Beast mode.
人間の状態では　まず
形態変化が難しくてできない。
Change in Chakra Form as
a human is impossible.
しかし…　回転を加えて
安定を増してるしかた！
If you add rotation,
it makes it more plausible.
でも　何か…。
Yeah, but...
ただの螺旋丸みてえに
上手くいかねえ…。
I can't do it as well as
my usual Rasengan.
尾獣チャクラは　プラスの青チャクラと→
Tailed Beast chakra is
a combination of
マイナスの赤チャクラの２つが
合わさってる…　そのバランス。
positive blue chakra and
negative red chakra.
Their ratio is key.
圧縮するとき　赤　青バランスを
２対８にすると球になる。
During compression, if you change
the red to blue ratio to 2:8,
it will become a ball!
やってみろ。
オッス！
Try it!
Okay!
まだまだだ　塩梅。
You haven't got it yet.
赤が９．５で青が０．５になっているぞ
簡単そうで難しい　案外。
Your red is at 9.5 and blue is 0.5!
It looks easy, but it's hard.
急にプラスとかマイナスとか
赤青チャクラとか→
All of a sudden,
there's talk of positive and negative,
数字がどうとか言われても
よくわかんねえよ。
red and blue chakra, and numbers...
I don't understand this stuff!
それに　この螺旋丸重くて
両手で支えねえと→
Besides, this Rasengan is heavy.
I have to use both hands
or it'll break apart.
すぐに乱れちまうから
んな細けえこと→
気にしてらんねえ。
I can't be bothered with
all those details.
俺ってば　体で覚えるタイプだからよ
だから　この尾獣螺旋丸。
I'm the type that learns
by doing things.
So as for this Tailed Beast Rasengan,
できるまで何度もやって　やって
やりまくって　ものにすんぜ！
I'm gonna keep doing it
and doing it...
Until I get it right!
人間では無理があるな　重労働。
It's impossible in human form...
it's a tougher toil.
少し休め　両手の傷が術の反動。
Rest a bit.
The wounds on your hands
are a type of jutsu recoil.
細けえことは
気にしてらんねえつっただろ！
I told you, I can't worry
about the details.
タコのおっさんが
２対８になるよう見てて→
Octopops, you said the ratio
should be 8:2.
ちょうどのところで言ってくれ。
Keep watching me and
tell me when I get it...
俺ってば
それを感覚で覚えっから！
I want to remember
what that feels like!
強情なやつだ　了解！
You sure are a persistent guy.
俺がお前に言ったことは自戒。
Very well.
I take back what I said.
（マダラ）まだ生きているようだな。
Looks like that woman is still alive.
（カブト）この女は
大蛇丸様の呪印に適合し→
Lord Orochimaru's Curse Mark
has adapted to this woman...
大蛇丸様のチャクラを
体内に持っている。
His chakra flows through her body now.
まだ殺せない。
（マダラ）駄目だ。
She can't be killed yet.
今ここで始末しろ。
No, get rid of her now.
この女は俺たちのアジトの
正確な場所と入り口を見ている。
This woman knows where
the real entrance to our hideout is.
生きたまま大蛇丸様のチャクラを
吸い取り　回収する必要がある。
I need to extract Lord Orochimaru's chakra
while she is alive
and collect it.
僕の体は
大蛇丸様の体と言ってもいい。
You might as well call
my body Lord Orochimaru's.
僕自身の力を
向上させるためには絶対だ。
It's crucial in order to increase
my own strength.
そうすれば
穢土転生を縛る力も強くなる。
Then my power to bind
the Reanimation Jutsu will increase.
それと更に重要なのは→
And another crucial thing is...
この術は生きた人間の体を使う。
This jutsu requires a live human body.
この女を生かしておくのは
そういうことだ。
That is why this woman is
being kept alive.
より戦力を増すことが
君への貢献度を→
Increasing our battle strength...
増すことになるだろう　違うかい？
Doesn't that further your cause?
Or am I wrong?
今日の友は明日の敵
かもしれん。
Today's friend is tomorrow's foe.
That may be so.
お前の利で　こちらが不利になる
可能性もある。
Your benefit could turn into
my disadvantage.
まだ信用されてないみたいだね
どうしろと？
You still don't trust me, do you?
穢土転生の術。
What do you want from me?
Prove to me right now
それが本当に生きた体を使うのか
ここで証明しろ　それと→
that the Reanimation Jutsu
really requires living bodies.
その術のすべてを
ここで説明してもらおう。
And... tell me all of its secrets.
もちろん止め方もだ。
Including how to stop it!
嫌だと言ったら？
And if I refuse?
お前の欲しいものは
一生　手に入らないうえ→
You will never acquire what
you desire and
欲しいものが別なものになる。
what you desire will become
something else...
自分自身の命だ！
It will be your life!
《ここで輪廻眼を相手にするのは
まずいな。
It's not wise to take on someone
who uses Rinnegan right now.
僕にも　まだ切り札がある
焦ることもない》
Well, I still have a hand to play.
No need to rush it.
いいだろう　だが　ここには
生贄にする者はいない。
Fine...
But I don't have any sacrifices here.
この女は使えないと言ったよね。
As I said,
this woman cannot be used.
その人たちは確か…。
Those people are...?
ダンゾウの犬だ。
Danzo's dogs.
捕らえたときから　ずっと
写輪眼による幻術をかけている。
They've been under
a Sharingan-based genjutsu
from the time of their capture.
容赦ないですね。
You don't go easy, do you?
さぁ　術の用意はしてやった。
All right, I got things ready for you.
今　俺が殺したこいつを
こっちのやつを使って→
I killed this one.
Now use this other one and
do the Reanimation Jutsu.
穢土転生しろ。
♪～
初めに言っておく。
これは　口寄せの術に
分類される。
Let me say this first.
This is categorized as
a type of Summoning Jutsu.
死者の魂をあの世である
浄土からこの世→
I summon the soul of the dead person
from the afterlife to this plane.
穢土に口寄せする。
そのためには　まず
よみがえらせたい人間の一部→
To achieve that, I need a portion
of the one I want to revive.
一定量の肉体が必要だ。
A fixed portion of flesh.
個人情報物質である
体の一部がね。
A portion that contains
personal identification material.
それがないものは
穢土転生できない。
Without it, the Reanimation Jutsu
will not work.
更に魂が浄土にない者。
Furthermore, if the soul is
not in the afterlife...
つまり　魂そのものを
別の場所へ→
Namely, if the soul has been
sealed somewhere else,
封印されていた場合も
転生はできない。
they cannot be revived.
（カブト）かつて
大蛇丸様は　四代目火影を→
In the past,
Lord Orochimaru tried to bring back
the Fourth Hokage and failed.
転生しようとして失敗した。
すでに屍鬼封尽による
封印術で→
That was because the god of death
had already taken the Hokage's soul
魂は　死神が持っていたからだ。
with the sealing jutsu,
the Reaper Deal Seal.
そして　木ノ葉崩しのとき→
And the Third Hokage also
used the same jutsu
三代目火影　ヒルゼンも
同じ封印術をした。
during the destruction of
Hidden Leaf Village.
初代と二代目を道連れにしてね。
The First and Second Hokage
were taken along too...
つまり…　初代から四代目まで
穢土転生はできないということか。
So that means...
Reanimation Jutsu can't be used
on the First through Fourth Hokage?
あぁ…。
That's right...
いくつも転生させたけど→
I've brought many back to life...
個人情報物質を
集めるのは大変だったよ。
But it wasn't easy to harvest
their personal information material.
それって　つまり
死体探しだからね。
It's basically just grave robbing.
腐って誰だかわかりゃしない。
It's hard to identify decaying bodies...
失敗作もいくつも作った。
I had a lot of failures.
これが　術式か…。
So this is the jutsu formula?
こうやって生きた人間を
死んだ者の魂の器にする。
This is how you turn a living person
into a vessel for the dead one's soul.
そうすれば　穢土転生の完成だ。
Then the Reanimation Jutsu
is complete.
（トルネ）ハァハァ…　こ　これは！？
Th-This is...?!
この術は　忍世界において
最大最強の術と言っていいよ。
You can call this jutsu
the most powerful jutsu
in the shinobi world.
二代目火影が考案し
大蛇丸様が完成させた→
The Second Hokage devised it and
Lord Orochimaru perfected it.
この世に残る最大の遺産！
It's their greatest legacy
to the world!
この札で人格を抑え
一定の命令を与えれば→
I control his personality with this tag.
And once I assign his orders...
よみがえった者は
生前の能力が戻り→
All the abilities he had in life will
be restored to this decaying man.
更に死ぬことなく
僕の命令に従うコマとなる。
And he will become my puppet who
obeys my orders and cannot die.
もちろん　六道の輪廻眼や
イタチの写輪眼のような→
Naturally, even rare abilities like
the Rinnegan of the Six Paths
希少な能力もそのままにね。
and Itachi's Sharingan.
ただ　うちはシスイの死体は
どこにもなかったし。
But I could not find
Shisui Uchiha's body anywhere.
自来也の死体は
人の入れない水圧の深海の中。
Jiraiya's body is deep in the ocean
where the pressure is too strong
for anyone to venture in.
ダンゾウの右目や
六道ペインたちの武器になら→
As for weapons like Danzo's right eye
and Pain of the Six Paths,
まだ　彼らの個人情報物質が
それなりに…。
I don't have all the materials
with their personal information.
図に乗るな。
Don't get carried away.
まあいいや。
もう手ゴマは十分か。
Well, no matter.
We have more than enough pawns.
これだけ都合のいい術だ。
何かリスクがあるはずだ。
A jutsu this ideal has to have risks.
ククク…　何よりこの術の
すばらしいのは→
The most amazing thing
about this jutsu is that...
術者に何のリスクもないことだ。
there is no risk for the jutsu user.
何だと？
What?
本当さ。
穢土転生の術に　リスクはない。
It's true.
The Reanimation Jutsu has no risk.
Well, it does have one.
いや　ひとつだけあったかな。
あまりにすばらしく
強い術のため→
Because it is such
an amazing, powerful jutsu,
術者の名が
世間の隅々まで行き渡る。
the name of its wielder will spread
to every corner of the world.
僕は　いずれ　うちはマダラよりも
有名な忍になる。
In name, I will be more famous
than Madara Uchiha.
インテリの僕は
そんなこと望んでないんだよ。
But an academic like me
has no desire for fame.
狙われるだけだしね。
I'll just become a target.
図に乗るなと言っている。
Don't get ahead of yourself!
物事には　すべてに反動がある。
There is a reaction to every action.
気を抜かずにいることだ。
Stay focused.
忠告　ありがとう。
I appreciate your advice.
この術のリスクがあるとすれば→
If this jutsu has a risk,
君に話してしまっていることが
リスクさ。
it's that I've given you information
about it.
じゃあ　そろそろ　僕も行くよ。
Well, I must be going.
インテリは　陰気なところが
性に合うんでね。
Academics are better suited
to be in gloomy places.
待て！　まだ　穢土転生の術の
止め方を聞いていないぞ。
Hold it!
You didn't tell me how to stop
the Reanimation Jutsu yet.
あっ　そうだったね。
忘れるところだった。
Oh! That's right.
I almost forgot.
この術は　術者を殺したとしても
止まることがない。
Killing the jutsu user
won't stop this jutsu.
なら　どうする？
So what do you do?
なに簡単さ。
It's quite easy really.
穢土転生を操っている僕を操り→
You manipulate me, the one
who controls the Reanimation Jutsu...
戌　午　寅の印で
解をして止めればいいのさ。
into breaking the jutsu by weaving
the signs... dog, horse and tiger.
例えば　君の写輪眼とかでね。
With your Sharingan, for instance.
あとは　穢土転生たちの魂を
封印するとかかな。
Otherwise, you can seal away
the souls of those under
the Reanimation Jutsu.
それが本当だといいがな。
That's fine and good, if it's true.
君に嘘をつく勇気は　ないよ。
I'm not brave enough to lie to you.
と　話はここまで。
ちゃんと　止め方は話した。
Anyway, this conversation is over.
I've told you how to stop it.
もう行くよ。
I'm going.
《穢土転生と　もうひとつの
あの術があるかぎり　僕は無敵だ。
As long as I have that other jutsu
along with the Reanimation Jutsu,
I am invincible.
いずれは　六道仙人の真理を
僕が解き明かしてみせる》
In time, I will unravel the truth
of the Sage of Six Paths.
あいつに
白ゼツの胞子は付けてあるな？
Is White Zetsu's spore tailing him?
もちろんだ。
Of course.
なら　黒ゼツ…　お前は　そろそろ
あっちのほうの段取りをしろ。
Then Black Zetsu, you can start
preparations for that other thing.
（ゼツ）わかった。
Understood.
油女ムタの情報がなければ
感知し損なうところだった。
I would have missed this
without Muta Aburame's intel.
大群が地下を通ってきてる！
A large army is
approaching underground!
感知位置を
もっと下へ広げるぞ！
We're going to widen our scope!
やつら　こちら連帯の足元を
素通りしてくるつもりだ！
They're going to try to pass
right under us!
連合連隊の後ろをとるつもりか？
Are they planning to take
the rear of the Allied Force?
（エー）土遁で掘り起こせ！
Use Earth Style and dig them up!
（オオノキ）すぐに　黄ツチに連絡じゃぜ。
Notify Kitsuchi immediately.
（いのいち）情報部隊
すぐに黄ツチに　このことを連絡だ。
Intel Unit!
Get word about it to
Kitsuchi immediately!
来た！
"INTEL UNIT SQUAD 1"
It's coming!
よし！
All right!
情報だ。
いよいよか。
"INTEL UNIT SQUAD 2"
New intel.
Finally.
敵　約２万。　座標　２５の３０。
"MAIN BATTLE REGIMENT,
SECOND COMPANY CAPTAIN KITSUCHI"
Enemy, roughly 20,000.
Coordinates: 25 by 30, underground!
地中です！
そうきたか。
So that's how they're coming.
（中吉）増援に…　来い。
Reinforcements...
（チヨ）穢土転生　二代目火影
扉間のときより洗練されておるな。
The Reanimation Jutsu...
It's more refined than the one
the Second Hokage Tobirama used.
これほど　一度に魂を操るとは
たいした輩よ。
To control this many souls
at one time...
It's quite a feat.
（ヒナタ）キバ君　シノ君！
Kiba! Shino!
（ネジ）早かったな　キバ。
That was fast, Kiba.
（キバ）こっちへ合流しろってよ。
I was told to join you here!
で　敵は近いのか？
Is the enemy near?
（２人）土遁！　開土昇堀！
– Earth Style! Erupt!
♪～
you and I held hands tightly and a light was born
kimi to boku nigirishimeta futatsu no te no naka de
let's release it now
umareta hikari ima hanatou
the town, tinged amber by the sunset
kohaku iro no yuuyake ni somerareta
projects a sad light and shadow
machi wa kanashii hikari to kage utsushite ita
I've encountered and gotten tangled
ikutsu mono kiseki no ito
in so many miraculous threads
tsunagatte karamatte tadoritsuita yo
it all starts here and now
hajimeru no wa ima kono basho kara
it'll clear up after the rain, become that cloud
ame nochi hare ano kumo ni nare
and swim towards the present
ima wo oyoi de yuku
toss away the hesitation
sono kokoro shibaritsuketeru
that clings to your heart
tamerai furihodoite
you and I held hands
kimi to boku nigirishimeta
and deep inside
futatsu no te no naka de
is the eternal proof of you
kieru koto nai kimi no akashi
with our liberated hands
jiyuu na sono ryoute de
let's start again, from here
koko kara mata hajimeyou
Next Episode
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
So this is neither heaven nor hell.
美空ひばりです。
You shouldn't be here...
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Mister Kakashi, please stop us again!
I'm already dead. I died human!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "An Old Nemesis Returns"
An Old Nemesis Returns
Yeah, I know.
Tune in again!